Guide to the American Committee for Cultural Freedom Records TAM.023
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
American Committee for Cultural Freedom Records
1939-1957
TAM.023
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
8.25 linear feet (12 boxes)
The American Committe for Cultural Freedom was formed in the 1950s as an affiliate of the International Congress for Cultural Freedom and membership included prominent liberal and leftist artists and intellectuals across a broad political spectrum. The group's activity involved the organization and execution of numerous anti-communist campaigns and programs. As Cold War tensions diffused, the group disolved. This collection includes the Committee's minutes, publications, proceedings of conferences, financial records, and files dealing with its relationship with Arthur Miller, Jean Paul Sartre, and Bertrand Russell.
American Committee for Cultural Freedom.
Box 1-12
Provenance
Gift of the American Committee for Cultural Freedom, ca. 1968.
Access Restrictions
Open for research; for access to Box 16 consult with Archives staff.
Historical/Biographical Note
Committee of prominent artists and intellectuals organized as the U.S. affiliate of the Congress for Cultural Freedom in 1950, but with roots in a long dormant domestic organization, the Committee for Cultural Freedom (1939-1940). Activities and programs on behalf of cultural freedom were generally informed by the staunch anti-communist orientation associated with the height of the Cold War period. Variant responses to the mid-1950's waning of these Cold War tensions led first to disaffiliation with the international organization and finally to formal dissolution in 1957. At the height of its activities, scores of artists and intellectuals across a surprisingly broad political spectrum were involved with the Committee either as invited members, as participants in its numerous campaigns and programs, or as correspondents. In leadership roles and among the most significant correspondents were Daniel Bell, James T. Farrell, Sidney Hook, Irving Kristol, and Diana Trilling. Less actively involved but well represented by letters are Robert Oppenheimer, David Reisman, Arthur Schlesinger Jr., and Norman Thomas. Negative responses to membership invitations include Hannah Arendt and James Conant.
Scope and Content Note
The collection is organized into three series: I. Congress for Cultural Freedom (CCF); II. Committee for Cultural Freedom; III. American Committee for Cultural Freedom (ACCF). The ACCF series comprises some 90% of the collection, and is organized into ten subseries: A. Correspondence, General; B. Corporate Records; C. Financial Affairs; D. Administrative Structure; E. Relations with Affiliated Organizations; F. Public Activities (Topics, Individuals, Misc.); G. Proposals and Projects That Failed to Materialize; H. Miscellaneous Activities; J. Miscellaneous; K. Clippings.
For the Congress for Cultural Freedom the records consist of a very small sampling of minutes and publications and a substantial array of the proceedings of conferences and congresses held all over the world from 1950 to 1956. Additional material concerning the CCF is located in those ACCF files dealing with its relationships with affiliate organizations. Records for the American Committee for Cultural Freedom include extensive files of minutes, correspondence, corporate and financial records. Documentation of public activities is similarly extensive. These include ACCF generated arts festivals, forums and petition campaigns; advocacy interventions in visa cases, deportations and loyalty-security hearings; the often unsuccessful courting of foundation grants for a wide range of activities; and numerous instances in which the Committee took on the role of warning intellectuals engaged in particular non-ACCF programs in defense of cultural freedom that they were allying themselves with politically tainted persons. Other instances of disparate responses among the intellectual community to Cold War issues are documented in the final subseries of the records in such files as those dealing with the Committee's relationship with Arthur Miller, Bertrand Russell, and Jean Paul Sartre. Note that the same correspondents may appear in both the Administrative Affairs subseries (general correspondence), and in the Public Activities subseries. Other notable correspondents (rep;resented by individual folders) include: Norman Jacobs, David Reisman, Clinton Rossiter, George S. Schuyler, Stephen Spender, Gleb Struve, Harold Urey, and Karl Wittfogel. NOTE: The Committee contacted prominent figures in literature, the arts and the sciences, and replies from a number of notable individuals may be found in the correspondence folders labeled simply with the letters of the alphabet, for example, under "C" are two brief letters from Whittaker Chambers.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: I. Congress for Cultural Freedom (CCF); II. Committee for Cultural Freedom; III. American Committee for Cultural Freedom (ACCF) and Restricted Material.
Folders are generally arranged alphabetically within each series.
Separated Material
Separated: Joseph Gordon Manuscripts and Correspondence (Collection number: Tamiment 82).
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives AND elsewhere
Papers of Daniel Bell, 190-1989; Harvard University Archives. See: http://hollis.harvard.edu/?itemid=|library/m/aleph|008437029
Bell, Daniel, 1919-; Congress for Cultural Freedom.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979; Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989; International Association for Cultural Freedom.; Kristol, Irving.; National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (U.S.).; Trilling, Diana; Anti-communist movements |z United States.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Minutes.; Proceedings.; Right and left (Political science)
- Series I: Congress for Cultural Freedom
  - Brussels Conference, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Berlin Conference, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Strasbourg Seminar, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Paris Arts Festival, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Milan Conference, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rangoon Conference, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mexico City Conference, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Soviet Invasion of Hungary- Protest, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Publications, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Submitted Reports and Articles, 1951-1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series II: Committee for Cultural Freedom (predecessor organization)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publications and Reports, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stationary Samples, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series III: American Committee for Cultural Freedom
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, General
    - Correspondence: A, 1952-1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Asia Foundation, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Aware, Inc., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: B, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: C, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: D, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: E, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: F, 1954-1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: James T. Farrell, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Ford Foundation, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Fund for the Republic, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Fund for the republic, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: G, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: H, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Sidney Hook, 1952-1956 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: International Rescue Committee, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: J, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Norman Jacobs, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: K, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Milton Konvitz, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Irving Kristol/ Encounter, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: L, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: M, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Robert Marshall Civil Liberties Trust, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: N, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: O, Dec 1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: P, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Merlyn Pitzle, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: R, 1952-1957 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: David Reisman, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Rockefeller Foundation, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Clinton Rossiter, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: S, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Arthur Schlesinger, Jr., 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: George S. Schuyler, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Stephen Spender, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Sol Stein, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Gleb Struve, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: T, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Norman Thomas, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Diana Trilling, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: U, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: U.S. Information Agency (Missing), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Harold Urey, 1953-1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: V, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Peter Viereck, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: W - Wh, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Wi - Wz, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Alan Furman Westin, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: C. Dickerman Williams, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: David C. Williams, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Karl Wittfogel, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: X - Y - Z, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Subseries B: Corporate Records
    - Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws, 1951-1956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ratification of By- Laws, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Policy Statements, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - New York State Registration as Charitable Organization, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Leases, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Personnel, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - WQXR Spot Announcement Contract, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: Financial Affairs
    - Auditors Reports, 1951-1955 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Festival Account, 1950-1952 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Tax-Related Materials, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Stock Transactions, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Fund Raising Campaign Contract, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Asia Foundation Grants (Reception Center), 1955-1957 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom- Financial Relations, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Fairfield Foundation, 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Robert Marshall Civil Liberties Trust- Financial Relations, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Subseries D: Administrative Structure
    - Boards of Directors, 1952-1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - James T. Farrell Resignation, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Minutes: Membership, Executive and Administrative Committees: Planning Conference: Board of Directors, 1950-1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Censorship Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Legal Commission, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Publishers Advisory Board, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Theater and Film Advisory Board, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Material Relating to Organizational Structure, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Subseries E: Relations With Affiliated Organizations
    - CCF: General, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - CCF: Stalin Philosophical Dictionary, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - CCF: Fleishman Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - CCF: Josselson Correspondence, 1952, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - CCF: Nabokov Correspondence, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Australia, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Brazil, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Burma, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Chile, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Cuba, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - France/ Preuves, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Germany, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Germany/ Monat, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - India, 1951-1956 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - India/ Ouest, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Indonesia, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Japan, 1951-1956 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Lebanon, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Mexico, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Pakistan, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Scandinavia, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Siam, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Letterhead Samples, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Referendum on ACCF Programs, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Membership Invitations- Negative Responses, 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Subseries F: Public Activities
    - Sub-subseries 1: Topics
      - Academic Freedom Statement, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - "Animal Farm" Film Promotion, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - "Anti-Americanism in Europe (conference), 1954 (Box 8, Folder 2A1)
      - Berlin Philharmonic Tour (Condemnation of Protest), 1955 (Box 8, Folder 2A2)
      - Books for Vietnam, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Broadcasts Behind Iron Curtain, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Chaplin Film Festival (Protest of Cancellation), 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Conference Series: Ideas, Stereotypes and the American Liberal- a Reexamination, Nov 1951Dec 1951 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Conference Series> Manuscripts, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Cultural Freedom Award, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - "Darkness at Noon" (Film Promotion), 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - "The Device of the United Front" (re Khrushchev's 'secret speech'), 1956 (Box 8, Folder 9A)
      - Facts Forum Radio Show Proposal (Protest), 1954 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Hungary/ College Tribute, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Hungary/ Petition Campaign, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Hungary/ Nobel Prize Winners' Protest, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Hungary/ "White Book", 1956 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Hungary/ Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Joliot- Curie Protest (Nobelists' Contesting Change of UN use of Germ Warfare in Korea), 1952 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Moscow University University Bicentennial Greetings, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - New Soviet Policy (Opinion Survey), 1956 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - "Nightmare in Red" (film promotion), 1956 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - "Reception Center"- Asia- Visitors (A-K), 1952-1957 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - "Reception Center"- Visitors (L-Z), 1955-1957 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - "Reception Center"- Jules Romain Reception, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - "Reception Center"- Spring Forum, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - "Reception Center"- Spring Forum, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - "Reception Center"- Spring Forum, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - "Reception Center"- Spring Forum, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - University Discussion Groups, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Venezuela Protest (UN Meeting Site), 1955 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - WEVD Radio Program, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Waldorf Astoria Conference- "In Defense of Free Culture", Mar 1952 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Waldorf Astoria Conference- "Anti-Americanism in Europe", Nov 1953 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Individuals' Cases
      - German Arciniegas Case (Detention at Ellis Island), 1953 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Argentine Protest (Arrest of Intellectuals), 1953 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - William Buckley/ Haverfort News Case (Ethical Issue), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Charlie Chaplin Case(Immigration Dept. Ruling), 1952 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Lowell Clucas Case (Loyalty Issue), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Alfred Sprague Coolidge Case (Employment), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Moshe Decter Case (Employment), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Milovan Djilas Case (Arrest and Book Burning), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Milovan Djilas/ Vladimir Dedijer Case(Indictment), 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Herbert Fuchs Case (Employment), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Bert Holland Case (security Clearance), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Thaddeus Jarecki Case (Polish Emigre), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Chris A. Jecchinis Case (Visa Denial), 1956 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Kalmuck Delegation (Visa Problems) - See also: Tamiment collection# 29, Kalmuck Resettlement Committee Records, 1950-51, 0.5 linear feet, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Arthur J. Kraus Case(Passport Revocation), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Edward Labin Case (Visa Denial), 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Wolf Ladejinsky Case (Security), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Edward Lamb Case (FCC License Denial), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Charles Lazoff Case(Employment), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - David Lerner Case(Loyalty), 1953 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Napthali Lewis Case (Scholarship Denial), 1953 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Alfred Lilienthal Case (Radio Program Cancellation), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Elinor Lipper-Catala Case (Visa Problem), 1951 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Joseph Lobodowski Case (Polish Emigre), 1955 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Val R. Lorwin Case (Loyalty), 1954 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Kingsley Martin Case (Academic Freedom), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Barry Miller Case (Undesirable Discharge from U.S. Army), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Czeslaw Milosz Case (Visa Denial), 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Alberto Moravia Case (Visa Denial), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - J. Robert Oppenheimer Case (Loyalty-Security), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Michael Polanyi Case (Visa Denial), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Ezra Pound Case (Institutionalization), 1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Reed College Cases (Academic Due Process), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Wilhelm Reich Case (Destruction of Personal Library), 1956 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Klaus Romppanen Case (Deportation), 1956 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Milton Sacks Case (Passport Restriction), 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - David Sills Case (Security), 1953 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Stephen Spender Case (Visa Denial), 1953 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Symphony of the Air (Tour Cancellation), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - W. Lou Tandy Case (Academic Freedom), 1953 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - James Wechsler Case (Employment), 1952 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Miscellaneous
      - ACCF Bulletin, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - ACCF Newsletters, 1953-1956 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "A Memorandum on the Visa Muddle", 1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Missing, 0000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - McCarthy and the Communists: Book Reviews and Notices, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Alfred Kohlberg Correspondence, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Owen Lattimore Libel Charges, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Press Releases, 1951-1954 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Self-Taught Negro Artists (exhibit, NYC), 1954 (Box 12, Folder 8A)
  - Subseries G: Proposals & Projects that Failed to Materialize
    - Anti-Intellectualism in the U.S. (Book Proposal), 1953 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Book Distribution Project, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Committee of 100 Against Communist Inhumanity- Contracts and Finances, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Committee of 100 Against Communist Inhumanity- Organization and Program, 1952-1954 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Committee of 100 Against Communist Inhumanity- Clippings, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Communism in the U.S.A. (Documentary Film Proposal), undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Cultural Assistance to Hungarian Refugees Proposal, 1956-1957 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Heresy Fund Proposal, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Human rights Commission Proposal, 1956-1957 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Intellectual Freedom Fund Proposal, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - International Affairs Anthology (Textbook Proposal), 1956 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Magazine Fellowship Fund Proposal, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 20A)
    - Magazine Conference Proposal, 1953-1954 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - "Opinion Abroad" (Journal Proposal), 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Patterson Project (Handbook on World Conspiracy), 1954 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Project for the Study...[of] Strategy in the Struggle Against International Communism, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Proposal to Study History...of Communist Influence...on Large Non-Communist Sectors of American Population, 1954-1956 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Proposal to Study Communist Party Influence in the Field of Civil Liberties, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Proposal to Study Effect...of government Security and Loyalty Regulations and Procedures, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Proposal to Study Use and Abuse of Fifth Amendment, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Proposal to Study Organized Extremist Groups in U.S., undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Soviet Arts, 1952-1955 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "Sport in Art" Tour, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Theater Union Study Proposal, 1954-1955 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - WQXR Radio Series Proposal, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Subseries H: Miscellaneous Activities
    - "Bibliography of the Communist Problem in the U.S." (Criticism), 1955 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Warnings to Sponsors of Various Programs of ECLC's Communist Ties, 1953-1954 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - HUAC Hearings on California Musicians (Identification of Communist Ties of Protest Group), 1956 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - HUAC Hearings on John Cogley's Blacklisting Study (Protest), 1956 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Owen Lattimore Case (Protest Against New Republic Article Supporting Lattimore), 1954-1956 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - The Nation Libel Suit Against the New Leader(Support for the New Leader), 1951-1954 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Post Office Censorship Protests, 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Proznan Uprising 1956 (Activities in Support of Insurrectionists) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Reece Committee Investigation of Tax-Exempt Foundations (Protest), 1954 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Rumanian Anti-Communist Siezing of Embassy (Commendation), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "360 Petition" to Void Internal Security Act (Denunciation), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Harold Urey Testimonial (Protest Sponsors' Communist Ties), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars (Protest Norwalk Chapter's Vigilantism), 1954 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Wages of Fear" (Protest Showing of Film with Communists in Cast), 1955 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Subseries J: Miscellaneous
    - Fund for the Republic / ACCF Controversy, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Joseph P. Kamp Attacks on ACCF, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Arthur Miller / ACCF Relations, 1954-1956 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Eugene Rabinovitch / James Burnham Controversy (Atomic Energy), 1953 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Bertrand Russell / ACCF Relations, 1953-1956 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Jean-Paul Sartre / ACCF Controversy (Sobell Case), 1956 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Submitted Ms.- Anthony Bouscaren; Guillermo Brown; George S. Counts; Christopher Emmet, 1954-1956 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Submitted Ms.- Philip Linnik; Dwight McDonald; Norbert Muhlen; John P. Roche; Gleb Struve; Ernest van der Haag, 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Photos: Robert Gorham Davis; Norbert Muhlen, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Americans for Intellectual Freedom; Friends of Russian Freedom, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 18)